Portfolio LinkedIn Github StackOverflow Writings

SUMMARY

Software artisan (Web2/Web3) and author with media and e-governance experience.

SKILLS

Languages: JS/TypeScript, Python, Processing, Solidity, HTML, CSS, Ruby ...

Frontend: React, NextJS, Svelte, SvelteKit ...

Backend: NodeJS, Express, FastAPI, NestJS, Flask, Rails ...

Tooling: WebPack, Vite, Babel, WebAssembly ...

Datastores: Postgres, SQL/GraphQL, MongoDB, Firebase, Redis, DynamoDB, IDB Operations: *nix/osx, Docker, AWS, GCP, Cloudflare, Azure, DigitalOcean ...

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Developer (evenzero.in) Independent Contractor, Remote/India Jun 2018 - Present

Full Stack Web Development Services

- Shipping with self-effacing transparency and flawless precision commercial, open-source, and bespoke web products to global business teams, YC alumni, and small businesses
- Specialties: Developer experience and tooling, Domain-specific solutions, Front-End, Content Strategy, APIs and API integration, QC, Cross-platform browser extensions
- Industries Served: Web3, Ed-tech, Fashion-tech, E-retail, Sales-tech, Fintech
- Clientele:
 - Holdex, Hong Kong Full stack Web3 development
 - Cybrilla, Bengaluru Modernised fintech API, email-service, design library
 - Able, Hyderabad Bespoke front-end project with a premier agency
 - Tattle, New Delhi Open-source WhatsApp Scraper with CMS
 - Salesbeat, UK AWS project for sales automation SaaS product
 - Singularium, Bengaluru Product front-end for an Azure cognitive service
 - Bombay Shirt Company, Mumbai Client-side optimisations on factory-to-customer e-retail solution
 - Autoproctor/Socratease, Bengaluru YC2021 New features, landing page
 - Sense Infinity, Bengaluru Restaurant loyalty management portal

Correspondent (Equity) NSE Cogencis, Mumbai Nov 2016 – Jun 2018

Content Strategy, Python, Excel

- Reporting business news in a real-time environment, interviewing CXOs-to-analysts of Technology, Media, Telecom sectors
- Monitoring and interpreting companies' financial results and earnings cycles (including previews and reviews), macro-developments, themes, and sector-wide trends, AGMs, EGMs, briefings and junkets
- Automating routine copies for the wire using existing data
- Cultivating relationships with investors, industry contacts, investor relations personnel, and senior management

Professional Ghostwriter Self-Employed, Chandigarh ${\rm Jan}\ 2015 - {\rm Sep}\ 2016$

Content Strategy

• Turning intellectual property into books, websites, content for global clientele on Upwork and Elance

Account Manager (Trainee)

Feb 2015 – Feb 2016

Goldentouch Consulting Ltd, Tel Aviv

UI/UX, Kindle publishing, Udemy

- Project Management/UI Design of a new Learning app
- Liaised with a development agency on a mobile application prototype
- Co-authored a book based on a top-selling Udemy course

Content Strategist / Bid Manager Redlizard Studioz, Chandigarh Oct 2014 - Feb 2015

macOS, Python

- Designing content strategy (white papers, corporate communications) for Video Games, E-commerce apps and web-apps
- Working with developers for editorial directions to in-game/in-app copy/UI/UX

Upper Division Clerk

Sep 2012 – Mar 2014

Employees' State Insurance Corporation, Ludhiana

Linux, Excel

- Calculating and disbursing physical disability pensions to victims of industrial accidents
- Working with doctors at ESIC hospitals in assessing physical disability arising out of industrial accident

EDUCATION

Bachelor Of Computer Applications Punjab Technical University, Jalandhar

2003 - 2006

CERTIFICATIONS

- Microsoft AZ-104: Microsoft Azure Administrator
- Microsoft Certified Trainer

PUBLICATIONS

- The key to study skills: Simple Strategies to Double Your Reading, Memory, and Focus (Amazon)
- ZYT : An open-source cross-browser plugin for YouTube

HOBBIES

- Reading and writing. Poetry, philosophy, fiction, aphorisms.
- Solo travel.

REFERENCES

References are available on request